<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-17T19:26:37+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">コロナウィルス対策について</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="コロナウィルス対策について" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus.html">&lt;p&gt;皆さん、こんにちは。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;現在、カンファレンス開催に向けて全力で取り組んでいます。月末が待ちきれません！しかし、皆さんご存じの通り、コロナウィルスが広まっています。日本でも現在30人の感染者おり（内24人は中国からの帰国者）、治療を受けています。1名の方は亡くなっています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;カンファレンスは安全に行いたいと考えており、皆さんの協力が必要です。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以下の条件のいずれかに当てはまる場合、カンファレンスへの参加をご遠慮ください。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;直近2週間以内に中国へ訪問している&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;37度以上の熱がある&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;咳が出ている&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;会場では除菌シートおよび消毒液を提供します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;必要に応じてスピーカーの方がマスクを付けている、プログラムの一部変更が行われる可能性があります。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;皆さんの健康を祈っています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;中津川篤司, DevRelCon Tokyo 主催者&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">皆さん、こんにちは。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Measures of Coronavirus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus_en.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Measures of Coronavirus" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus_en</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/coronavirus_en.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re tackle to prepare conference successful. So we can’t wait looking forward to meet you.
However lately APAC has a problem of Coronavirus. In Japan, patiants are limited now, they got suitable treatment from hospital. There is totally 30 patiants (24 people are back from China) and 1 person is dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe our conference is safe, but we definitlly need your support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you match any conditions below, you CAN’T attend the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had visited China in 2 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a fever (37 ℃ or 98.6℉）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a cough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll prepare antiseptic solution and disinfection sheet at the conference venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we need it, speakers put on the masks, and will be changed the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I belive your helth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atsushi, organizer of DevRelCon Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">Hi all,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020中止のお知らせ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DevRelCon Tokyo 2020中止のお知らせ" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyoは国内外から多数の方が参加されるグローバルなカンファレンスです。今年に入ってから、日本におけるコロナウイルスの状況について心配する連絡を多数受けていました。企業によっては日本を含むAPACへの出張を取りやめる企業も出始めています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;日本と中国の状況は異なり、アジアという枠で一括りにしないで欲しいとは常々連絡していました。また、クルーズ船は国内とはまったく異なる状態であるとも説明してきました。日本におけるコロナウイルスは政府のコントロール下にあり、重病者もほとんどいませんでした。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;その状況が変わりはじめたのが先週くらいからです。国内ではじめて亡くなられた方がいると発表され、日々感染者も増えています。大規模イベントの自粛要請もはじまっています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyoは年一回のカンファレンスであり、国内にいながらグローバルなカンファレンスの雰囲気を味わえる唯一無二の機会となっています。DevRelCon Tokyoに参加する参加者、スピーカー、スポンサー、そして運営メンバー全員がカンファレンスを心の底から楽しいと感じ、DevRelの可能性を強く感じてもらうのが第一の目的です。現状のようなコロナウイルスに怯えながら、マスクや消毒液を常に気にするような中では楽しむことなど不可能でしょう。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;また、DevRelCon Tokyoは予算の関係もあり、IBMさんやYahoo! JAPANさんの場所を借りて実施される予定でした。もしカンファレンスを強行して、DevRelCon Tokyoがコロナウイルスを広げるきっかけになるというのは、会場を貸してくださる企業のブランディングにも傷を付けることになります。快く貸してくださっている企業に対して、そうした行為はとてもできません。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;そういった事情を踏まえた上で、メインの主催者である私（中津川篤司）の独断により、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020の中止を決定しました。全責任は私にありますので、何かあれば &lt;a href=&quot;atsushi@moongift.jp&quot;&gt;atsushi@moongift.jp&lt;/a&gt; までご連絡ください。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;なお、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020は私の中では死んではおりません。コロナウイルスの状況が不透明な中、確実なことを書くのは難しいのですが、2020年秋ごろ（オリンピック、パラリンピックが終わってから）を目安に、再度行えるように企画中です。こちらは詳しい状況が決まり次第、当サイト上やソーシャルアカウントを通じて発表します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devrelcontokyo&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/DevrelConTokyo/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;何よりDevRelCon Tokyoを楽しみにしていただいた方々を裏切る形になってしまったことが残念でなりません。半年後、今回の決定が間違っていなかったこと、そういうこともあったよねと語れる状態になっていることを期待します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;中津川篤司@DevRelCon Tokyo 2020主催者&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyoは国内外から多数の方が参加されるグローバルなカンファレンスです。今年に入ってから、日本におけるコロナウイルスの状況について心配する連絡を多数受けていました。企業によっては日本を含むAPACへの出張を取りやめる企業も出始めています。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo has been canceled</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled_en.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DevRelCon Tokyo has been canceled" /><published>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2020-02-14T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled_en</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2020/02/14/devrelcon-tokyo-has-canceled_en.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo is a global conference attended by many people from Japan and overseas. Earlier this year, We had many contacts to worry about the situation of coronavirus in Japan. Some companies have begun to cancel their business trips to APAC including Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always said, the situation in Japan and China was different. And I also explained that cruise ships are in a completely different state than in Japan. The coronavirus in Japan was under government control and few were seriously ill condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation began to change about last week. It has been announced that some people have died for the first time in Japan, and the number of infected people is increasing every day. Requests for self-restraint of large-scale events have also begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo is an annual conference, providing a unique opportunity to experience the atmosphere of a global conference while staying in Japan. The primary goal is to make sure that all participants, speakers, sponsors, and the operating members of DevRelCon Tokyo enjoy the conference from the bottom of their hearts and feel the potential of DevRel. It would be impossible to enjoy it if audiences are always put on a mask and disinfectant,  and being afraid of the current coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on such circumstances, I (Atsushi) decided to cancel DevRelCon Tokyo 2020. I have full responsibility, so if you have any questions, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;atsushi@moongift.jp&quot;&gt;atsushi@moongift.jp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 is not dead in me. While the situation of coronavirus is uncertain, it is difficult to write certainty. However we are planning to do it again around fall 2020 (after the Olympics and Paralympics). This will be announced on this site and through a social account as soon as details are determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/devrelcontokyo&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/DevrelConTokyo/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, it’s a shame that we have betrayed those who enjoyed DevRelCon Tokyo. Six months later, I hope that this decision was not wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atsushi@DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 Organizer&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo is a global conference attended by many people from Japan and overseas. Earlier this year, We had many contacts to worry about the situation of coronavirus in Japan. Some companies have begun to cancel their business trips to APAC including Japan.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcement for the hosting of DevRelCon Tokyo 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcement for the hosting of DevRelCon Tokyo 2020" /><published>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 is back! Last year in 2019, over 150 people from around the world participated at DevRelCon Tokyo 2019, but we will expand its scale even further. Here is a summary of some new endeavors at DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-will-be-a-two-day-conference&quot;&gt;There will be a two day conference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has only been a one day conference at DevRelCon Tokyo up to now, but it will be over two days (February 28th, 29th) for DevRelCon Tokyo 2020. On the 28th (Friday), it will be for businesses, and it will feature opinions from management of business and developer relations, team management, marketing, and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 29th (Saturday), it will be for developers, and the main theme will involve evangelists and advocates, the development community, DX (developer experiences), and such. Up to now, both sides were either combined, or if anything, there was more of a focus towards developers, but we believe that developer relations have to be tackled so as to grow businesses and understand developer relations as functions related to business, so we want to share that knowledge on the business day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-venue-will-be-at-yahoo-japan&quot;&gt;The venue will be at Yahoo! JAPAN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, DevRelCon Tokyo has rented Cybozu, Inc. as a wonderful venue, and foreign participants were also pleased with it. However, so as to expand its scale even more than up to now, we will now rent Yahoo! JAPAN to accommodate more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-more-interpretation-system-pamphlets-with-speech-details-will-be-prepared&quot;&gt;No more interpretation system. Pamphlets with speech details will be prepared&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, we have tried out simultaneous interpretation and an interpretation system, but they did not meet a satisfactory quality. That is why we have now done away with an interpretation system, and instead will conduct interviews before each speaker takes the podium so we can prepare pamphlets containing a summary of each speech’s contents (in Japanese and English). People will be able to understand the speech’s contents by reading that, so it will be helpful to comprehend English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-kids-room-will-be-prepared&quot;&gt;A kids room will be prepared&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, there have been a lot of people who have brought their children along with them when participating at DevRelCon Tokyo, but they would have been held personally liable if a problem occurred. Fortunately, there have not been any problems up to now, but a kids room is still indispensable for people to participate without any worries. That is why, although it may only be for the 29th (Saturday), a kids room will be prepared, and it will naturally be free to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it seems like it will be available to children at least 1 year old. We apologize for that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-projects-are-being-planned&quot;&gt;Other projects are being planned!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what has been decided at the present time. But even more projects will be prepared so as to further enliven DevRelCon Tokyo 2020. Please look forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 is back! Last year in 2019, over 150 people from around the world participated at DevRelCon Tokyo 2019, but we will expand its scale even further. Here is a summary of some new endeavors at DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 this time around.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020開催のお知らせ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DevRelCon Tokyo 2020開催のお知らせ" /><published>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo 2020が帰ってきました！前回の2019では世界中より、150名を超える方々が参加したDevRelCon Tokyo 2019ですが、さらに規模を拡大してお届けします。今回のDevRelCon Tokyo 2020での新しい試みを紹介します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2デーカンファレンスになります&quot;&gt;2デーカンファレンスになります&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでのDevRelCon Tokyoは1日だけのカンファレンスでしたが、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020では2デー（2月28日、29日）になります。28日（金）はビジネスデーとして、DevRelとビジネスにおける経営層からの視点、チームマネジメント、マーケティングなどについて取り上げます。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29日（土）はデベロッパーデーとして、エバンジェリストやアドボケイト、開発者コミュニティ、DX（開発者体験）などをメインテーマとします。これまでは両者を混合、またはどちらかと言えばデベロッパー向けの趣が強かったですが、DevRelをビジネス上の機能として捉えて、ビジネスを成長させていくためにDevRelに取り組まなければならないと考えており、そうしたナレッジをビジネスデーで共有したいと考えています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;場所がyahoo-japanになります&quot;&gt;場所がYahoo! JAPANになります&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでDevRelCon Tokyoはサイボウズ社をお借りしてきました。素晴らしい会場で、海外からの参加者からも喜んでもらえます。しかし、これまで以上に規模を拡大するため、さらに収容人数の多いYahoo! JAPANさんをお借りすることになりました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;通訳システムを廃止登壇詳細を記載した冊子を用意します&quot;&gt;通訳システムを廃止。登壇詳細を記載した冊子を用意します&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまで同時通訳や通訳システムを試してきましたが、満足な品質には及びませんでした。そこで、今年は通訳システム自体を廃止し、登壇前に各スピーカーにインタビューを行い、その登壇内容を紹介する冊子を作成します（日英版）。それを読むことで、登壇内容を把握できるようになります。そうすればスピーカーの英語を理解する助けになるでしょう。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;キッズルームを用意します&quot;&gt;キッズルームを用意します&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでのDevRelCon Tokyoでもお子様を連れて参加してくださる方が多かったですが、問題が起こった際には自己責任となってしまっていました。幸いにもこれまで問題は起こらなかったのですが、やはり安心して参加してもらうためにはキッズルームの存在が欠かせません。そこで今回は29日（土曜日）だけになってしまうと思いますが、キッズルームを用意します。もちろん無料でご利用いただけます。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;なお、年齢は1歳以上になってしまいそうです。すみません…。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;この他色々企画中&quot;&gt;この他色々企画中！&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;現時点で決まっているのはこれくらいです。ただ、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020をさらに盛り上げるためにも、もっとたくさんの企画を用意します。ぜひ楽しんでください！&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020が帰ってきました！前回の2019では世界中より、150名を超える方々が参加したDevRelCon Tokyo 2019ですが、さらに規模を拡大してお届けします。今回のDevRelCon Tokyo 2020での新しい試みを紹介します。</summary></entry></feed>