<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-20T22:01:17+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Announcement for the hosting of DevRelCon Tokyo 2020</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcement for the hosting of DevRelCon Tokyo 2020" /><published>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back-en.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 is back! Last year in 2019, over 150 people from around the world participated at DevRelCon Tokyo 2019, but we will expand its scale even further. Here is a summary of some new endeavors at DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-will-be-a-two-day-conference&quot;&gt;There will be a two day conference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has only been a one day conference at DevRelCon Tokyo up to now, but it will be over two days (February 28th, 29th) for DevRelCon Tokyo 2020. On the 28th (Friday), it will be for businesses, and it will feature opinions from management of business and developer relations, team management, marketing, and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 29th (Saturday), it will be for developers, and the main theme will involve evangelists and advocates, the development community, DX (developer experiences), and such. Up to now, both sides were either combined, or if anything, there was more of a focus towards developers, but we believe that developer relations have to be tackled so as to grow businesses and understand developer relations as functions related to business, so we want to share that knowledge on the business day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-venue-will-be-at-yahoo-japan&quot;&gt;The venue will be at Yahoo! JAPAN&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, DevRelCon Tokyo has rented Cybozu, Inc. as a wonderful venue, and foreign participants were also pleased with it. However, so as to expand its scale even more than up to now, we will now rent Yahoo! JAPAN to accommodate more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-more-interpretation-system-pamphlets-with-speech-details-will-be-prepared&quot;&gt;No more interpretation system. Pamphlets with speech details will be prepared&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, we have tried out simultaneous interpretation and an interpretation system, but they did not meet a satisfactory quality. That is why we have now done away with an interpretation system, and instead will conduct interviews before each speaker takes the podium so we can prepare pamphlets containing a summary of each speech’s contents (in Japanese and English). People will be able to understand the speech’s contents by reading that, so it will be helpful to comprehend English speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-kids-room-will-be-prepared&quot;&gt;A kids room will be prepared&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up to now, there have been a lot of people who have brought their children along with them when participating at DevRelCon Tokyo, but they would have been held personally liable if a problem occurred. Fortunately, there have not been any problems up to now, but a kids room is still indispensable for people to participate without any worries. That is why, although it may only be for the 29th (Saturday), a kids room will be prepared, and it will naturally be free to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it seems like it will be available to children at least 1 year old. We apologize for that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-projects-are-being-planned&quot;&gt;Other projects are being planned!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what has been decided at the present time. But even more projects will be prepared so as to further enliven DevRelCon Tokyo 2020. Please look forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 is back! Last year in 2019, over 150 people from around the world participated at DevRelCon Tokyo 2019, but we will expand its scale even further. Here is a summary of some new endeavors at DevRelCon Tokyo 2020 this time around.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020開催のお知らせ</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DevRelCon Tokyo 2020開催のお知らせ" /><published>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-10-06T16:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/information/2019/10/06/devrelcon-tokyo-is-back.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRelCon Tokyo 2020が帰ってきました！前回の2019では世界中より、150名を超える方々が参加したDevRelCon Tokyo 2019ですが、さらに規模を拡大してお届けします。今回のDevRelCon Tokyo 2020での新しい試みを紹介します。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2デーカンファレンスになります&quot;&gt;2デーカンファレンスになります&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでのDevRelCon Tokyoは1日だけのカンファレンスでしたが、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020では2デー（2月28日、29日）になります。28日（金）はビジネスデーとして、DevRelとビジネスにおける経営層からの視点、チームマネジメント、マーケティングなどについて取り上げます。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29日（土）はデベロッパーデーとして、エバンジェリストやアドボケイト、開発者コミュニティ、DX（開発者体験）などをメインテーマとします。これまでは両者を混合、またはどちらかと言えばデベロッパー向けの趣が強かったですが、DevRelをビジネス上の機能として捉えて、ビジネスを成長させていくためにDevRelに取り組まなければならないと考えており、そうしたナレッジをビジネスデーで共有したいと考えています。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;場所がyahoo-japanになります&quot;&gt;場所がYahoo! JAPANになります&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでDevRelCon Tokyoはサイボウズ社をお借りしてきました。素晴らしい会場で、海外からの参加者からも喜んでもらえます。しかし、これまで以上に規模を拡大するため、さらに収容人数の多いYahoo! JAPANさんをお借りすることになりました。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;通訳システムを廃止登壇詳細を記載した冊子を用意します&quot;&gt;通訳システムを廃止。登壇詳細を記載した冊子を用意します&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまで同時通訳や通訳システムを試してきましたが、満足な品質には及びませんでした。そこで、今年は通訳システム自体を廃止し、登壇前に各スピーカーにインタビューを行い、その登壇内容を紹介する冊子を作成します（日英版）。それを読むことで、登壇内容を把握できるようになります。そうすればスピーカーの英語を理解する助けになるでしょう。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;キッズルームを用意します&quot;&gt;キッズルームを用意します&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;これまでのDevRelCon Tokyoでもお子様を連れて参加してくださる方が多かったですが、問題が起こった際には自己責任となってしまっていました。幸いにもこれまで問題は起こらなかったのですが、やはり安心して参加してもらうためにはキッズルームの存在が欠かせません。そこで今回は29日（土曜日）だけになってしまうと思いますが、キッズルームを用意します。もちろん無料でご利用いただけます。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;なお、年齢は1歳以上になってしまいそうです。すみません…。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;この他色々企画中&quot;&gt;この他色々企画中！&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;現時点で決まっているのはこれくらいです。ただ、DevRelCon Tokyo 2020をさらに盛り上げるためにも、もっとたくさんの企画を用意します。ぜひ楽しんでください！&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="information" /><summary type="html">DevRelCon Tokyo 2020が帰ってきました！前回の2019では世界中より、150名を超える方々が参加したDevRelCon Tokyo 2019ですが、さらに規模を拡大してお届けします。今回のDevRelCon Tokyo 2020での新しい試みを紹介します。</summary></entry></feed>